m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
字　　幕　　侠
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
翻译　文生云　wanderlust　厨师沙拉
翻译　芋头　渣渣辉　独角马
校对　多星人　时间轴　iiichiii
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
监制　多星人
m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
永不者
第一季 第 4 集
马森工厂
伦敦 万德利哈姆路 圣赛西莉娅教堂
斯特普尼 格林 11点整
警察
玛拉黛
吉尔伯特・马森
德克兰・奥林 - 乞丐王
奥古斯都・毕德罗
拉维妮娅・毕德罗
圣罗毛尔
达孤儿院
我想要你加入我们
I want you to join us.
这就是你的使命吗
Is that the mission you were going on about?
你还是能感觉到的 玛丽的歌声
You still feel it. Mary's song.
你知道更好的世界是什么样
You know what a better world could be like.
玛丽第一次歌唱时
First time Mary sang,
只有屋里的附魔人能听到
only the Touched that were in the room could hear it.
我们会让玛丽唱得足够响亮
We'll make Mary's voice loud enough
响亮到城市另一头的附魔人都能听见
that it could be heard by Touched across the city.
我们得把传单全撕下来
We need to get those fliers taken down.
肯定在伦敦贴得到处都是
They could be all over London.
他们对那些女孩都做什么
What did they do to the girls?
人体实验
Experiments.
我们得查查他们在做什么
We need to know everything they've been doing.
你哪位
Oh! Who are you?
命令是除掉玛拉黛
The Order is to eliminate Maladie.
玛拉黛帮了我们大忙
Maladie has done us a favor.
她让人们对附魔之人的看法急转直下
She turned sentiment against the Touched.
我们被攻击 被囚禁 被丢弃到大街上
We're being attacked, locked up, and thrown in the street.
出现了我们尚未意识到的敌人
We have enemies you don't know about yet.
所有的附魔之人 他们会来到我们身边
The Touched, they'll all come to us.
他们会很安全
They'll be safe.
? 劳作的苦役已经结束 ?
? Now the laborer's task is o'er ?
? 斗争已成往事 ?
? Now the battle day is past ?
? 遥远的海滨上 ?
? Now upon the farther shore ?
? 航行者的身影终出现 ?
? Lands the voyager at last ?
? 天父啊 在你仁慈的庇护下 ?
? Father, in thy gracious keeping ?
? 安息吧 ?
? Leave we now ?
? 让我们的忠仆安息 ?
? Thy servant sleeping ?
? 彼岸之地 眼泪也已干涸... ?
? There the tears of Earth are dried... ?
卸货
Down!
? 彼岸之地 掩盖之物已浮出水面 ?
? There it's hidden things are clear ?
? 彼岸之地 ?
? There the work of life is tried ?
? 那是更公正之地 ?
? By a juster judge than here ?
? 彼岸之地 悔过者 ?
? There the penitents that turn ?
? 无神眼睛远望十字架 ?
? To the cross their dying eyes ?
? 上帝的爱 ?
? All the love of Jesus learn ?
? 伴随他步入天堂吧 ?
? At his feet in paradise ?
? 上帝啊 在你仁慈的庇护下 ?
? Father, in thy gracious keeping ?
? 安息吧 让我们的忠仆安息... ?
? Leave we now thy servant sleeping... ?
-女巫  -怪胎
- Witches! - Freaks!
-真该把你们都淹死 哈哈  -终于死了 谢天谢地
- Why don't we drown you all? Ha, ha! - Good riddance!
把她扔河里 看她会不会漂起来
Drown her! Let's see if she floats!
-肮脏的怪物  -走 都滚开
- Vile creatures! - Go on, piss off!
别这样 巡官 现在不是时候
Please, Inspector. Not now.
也别在这
Not here.
-你们被逮捕了  -给我走
- You're under arrest. - Come on, you two.
要这样是吧...
There we go...
我知道你比我们任何人都更难过
I know your loss is greater than any of us
-能...  -她他娘的在哪
- can even... - Where the fuck is she?
能够预见未来的那位女士在哪
Where's the lady who can see the future?
一个吻换一品脱酒 我们说好的
A kiss for a pint. That was the deal.
我从不食言
I am a woman of my word.
一个吻换一品脱酒
Kiss for a pint.
不是 你他妈别...
Oh, no, you fucking don't...
我一会再来找你
I'm gonna need you in a minute.
哪个是领头的
Who speaks for these men?
是他 阁下
Him, m'lord.
雅各布斯
Jacobs.
他们发现货物里有炸药
The men learnt there are explosives among the cargo here.
他们要求更高的报酬 才愿意运这批货
They feel they're due higher wages for handling them.
这里有人知道这是什么吗
Who here knows what this is?
是炮弹 阁下
Well, that's a shell, sir.
里面装着无烟线状火药 用来打仗的
Loaded with cordite. Ready for the war.
完全正确
Top marks.
这是用来炸死敌人
It's good for blowing up the enemy,
保护同胞的
and for saving our lads.
这就是被你们扣住的人质 你们的同胞
That's who you're holding hostage here. Your brothers.
-但这改变不了事实...  -老天爷啊
- That doesn't change the facts... - Jesus!
如果这些炸药不稳定
If they were unstable,
我们直接把它们滚过边境不就胜利了吗
we would simply roll them over the line, wouldn't we?
你们不过是想找机会发牢骚
You men are seeking a grievance.
码头上有的是关心军队同胞的自己人
The docks are full of men who care about our troops,
和什么都不在乎的外国人
and foreigners who care about nothing.
我一小时内就能找人换掉你们
I can fill your jobs in an hour!
回去干活 我就当什么都没发生
Get back to work, and I will forget this happened.
既往不咎
No repercussions.
也不会因这次罢工扣工资
You won't be docked for this stoppage.
已经很宽宏大量了
It's very generous.
走吧 走吧 回去工作
Go on. Go on. Back to work.
走吧 走
Go on. Go on.
再有下次 自己来跟我谈
Next time, come and talk to me as individuals.
混在大伙中间当缩头乌龟算什么本事
To band together when you could stand alone?
我希望能在英国人身上看到更多的勇气
I expect more courage from Englishmen.
他们就吃这套 阁下
They're taking the carrot, my lord.
他们现在是吃下了这套
They're mouthing the carrot.
如果出尔反尔 我们再上大棒
They spit it back out, we'll use the stick.
我以为安尼尔跟你在一起呢
I thought Aneel was with you.
他得回学校去
He had to get back to school.
我是说 他上学去了
I mean, he gets to.
可以的话 我想请你帮个忙
If you're up to it, I need a favor.
那些新来的人
The new folk,
有传言说 还有一两个人身背逮捕令
there's rumors one or two have outstanding warrants.
都不是大事 很有可能是编造出来的
Petty charges, likely cooked up.
大概就是些罚款吧
It should mostly just be fines, I imagine.
严格来说 他们中一些人不是公民
Some of them might not technically be citizens.
他们不都说英语 所以很难分辨
They don't all speak English, so it's hard to tell.
我不清楚这有没有影响 我先查查
I don't know if that matters, but I'll find out.
-你真是人美心善  -我更希望做个律师
- You're a daisy. - I'd rather be a barrister.
这样我就可以起诉那些...
Then I could prosecute the men...
现在应该没办法了
I don't see how, though.
安尼尔的学校我都没法申请
I can't even apply to Aneel's school.
如果无法成为司法的一环
How are we ever gonna see justice
我们要如何寻求正义呢
if we're not a part of justice?
我能看透的也就只有葡萄了
All I can see my way through is a grape.
你知道你得把这些碎片都清理干净吧
You know you're gonna have to clean up those shards, right?
嗯
Yeah.
所以 就是这样吗
So, is this what we can expect?
一个德不配位的领袖
A leader who doesn't lead?
你是想取而代之吗
Are you looking to fill that position?
她的房间确实最舒服
She does have the nicest room.
你知道特鲁本应该出席葬礼的
You know True should have been there.
连绑架过玛丽的我 都对她表示更多尊重
I've shown more respect for Mary, and I'm her kidnapper.
阿玛莉亚虽然经常不拘小节
Amalia misses the point of things, as often as not.
如果她坐的时候发现椅子是热乎的
But if that chair is warm when she sits in it,
她会懂的
she'll know why.
你觉得我比不过她吗
You don't think I can best her?
我觉得你不会想做这份工作
I don't think you want her job.
让人筋疲力竭
It's very draining.
在葬礼上你有看到什么奇怪的人吗
Did you see anyone out of place at the funeral?
玛拉黛不在 也没有那群混混
Not Maladie. None of the gang.
乞丐王送来了花圈
Beggar King sent a wreath.
-特别大的那个  -她是失去了朋友
- The great big one? - She lost a friend.
又不是赢了德比赛马
She didn't win the Derby.
那个大的没有署名
Big one wasn't signed.
几个纯化论者在那边丢人现眼
Couple of Purists making a fuss.
你应该看到了
You probably saw.
穿着粉红色的破衣烂衫
The pink rags.
-纯化论者都有  -他们都给自己取名了吗
- Purists all have them. - So they have a name now?
-上帝保护我们  -那不是我要干的事吗
- Christ preserve us. - Thought that was my job.
我们不想要更多暴力事件了
We don't want more violence.
这可是伦敦 医生
This is London, Doctor.
总会有更多的
There's always more.
我还是不明白你是怎么从为玛拉黛效力...
I still don't see how you can go from working for Maladie...
到跟阿玛莉亚站在一边
to being here with Amalia.
你真的觉得她们有什么不同吗
You really think they're that different?
特鲁还没回来吗
True still not back?
我发誓 我...
I swear to Jesus, I would...
你们还没说完我的缺点吗
Have you not finished discussing my faults?
走吧 派南斯 上帝等着呢
Come on, Penance. Jesus awaits.
他已经知道我要说什么
He already knows what I was gonna say,
我后面再补点玛丽的颂词之类的
and I'll add a few Hail Marys for that later.
弗兰克・蒙迪也需要说几句 可怜的人啊
Frank Mundi'll owe a few himself, poor man.
玛拉黛没出现在葬礼上
Maladie didn't show at the funeral.
你敢相信那女人有多狠心吗
Can you believe the rudeness of that woman?
她出现才是疯了 还不是她那种疯
It'd be madness to show, and not her kind.
报道这次枪击案的报纸都是在谴责她
The papers that bothered to report on the shootin' are all blamin' her,
我们也不知道到底是不是她做的
and we don't know that we shouldn't be.
我还是觉得她会去
I still thought she might go.
那你为什么没去呢
So why didn't you?
想淹死我的是尼古拉斯・珀巴尔
The man who tried to drown me is Nicholas Perbal.
那个山顶洞人
Ach. That brute?
能在水上行走 却是为了杀人
The blasphemy of walking on water
-简直是亵渎神明...  -他姓奥迪恩
- for the purpose of murder... - He's called Odium.
他亲爱的奶奶可不这么叫
Not by his dear Granny Perbal,
她在海峡某处有间舒适小阁楼
who owns a snug little attic somewhere in the narrows.
乞丐王说他正在养伤 很可能就在他奶奶家
Beggar King's man says he's convalescing, likely at Gran's.
小提琴很贵吗
Do violins cost a lot?
你和玛丽的两起袭击事件可能并无关联
The two attacks could be unrelated, you and Mary.
-我听说很多人不喜欢你  -我知道
- Lot of people don't like you, I'm told. - I know.
战争的受害者...
A casualty of war...
我要泡个澡
I need a bath.
告诉露西我们一小时后见
Tell Lucy we're meeting in an hour.
列嫌疑人名单
Start listing suspects.
但她是所有女孩中最伤心的
But she's broken up worst of all the girls.
我们要转移她的注意力
We'll take her mind off it.
所有人都要出力 而她是最得力的一个
It's all hands on deck, and she has the best hands in the group.
在此期间...
In the meantime...
不用拘束
Make yourself comfortable.
特鲁 你该去参加葬礼的
Ah, True, sure and you should've been at the service.
你给女孩们做了坏榜样
You're a bitter poor example to the girls.
但我如此顽强和刻薄 我讨厌儿女情长
But I'm so tough and mean, and I hate sentiment.
还讨厌人 以及我自己
And also people. And myself.
老天 玛丽・布莱顿信任你
Ah, Lord, Mary Brighton trusted you,
-而你却让她失望了  -你是这么觉得的吗
- and you failed her. - Is that what you think?
我觉得我们寻找凶手的时间越长
I think the longer we wait to find the killer,
就越有可能永远找不到他
the greater the chance we never do.
玛丽可不需要我对着她的尸体哭泣
Mary doesn't need me crying over her corpse.
特鲁 我无法想象你参加过多少场葬礼 但...
True, I can't imagine how many funerals you've been to, but...
一次都没有 我们那儿不办葬礼
None. We don't do that when I'm from.
我们没时间 地也不够埋
We don't have enough time and we don't have enough ground.
你比任何人都清楚
You know better than anyone what pain does
如果不花时间消解痛苦 它会带来什么
when you don't make time for it.
时间只会不断流逝
All time does is run out.
我当初被丢在这里 无依无靠
I was left here, completely alone,
除了从未被真正赋予的任务以外 一无所知
with nothing but a mission I was never actually given.
没有命令 没有目标...
No orders, no objectives...
他们把我丢在这儿 然后就他妈转身离开
They left me here and they fucked right off.
也许他们死了 谁管呢 但我在这里...
Maybe they died. Who cares? I'm here...
一个女人会因发声而被杀死的地方
where a woman can be killed just for having a voice,
如果我不做点什么阻止情况变得更糟的话
which will be the world's fucking epitaph
这他妈将成为整个世界的墓志铭
if I can't do something other than make it worse.
我知道你肩负重任 特鲁
I know your burdens, True. But is vengeance
但复仇就能让世界变得更好吗
going to make the world better?
如果我们... 查出是谁夺走了玛丽
If we... if we find out who took away our Mary,
我对你下一步采取的行动感到担忧
I have a worry as to your next course of action,
因为我们其他人 都有机会和她好好道别...
because the rest of us, we had a chance to say goodbye...
记住她善良的心
To remember the goodness of her heart,
而不只是她被夺走的不公
and not just the unfairness of her being taken.
你一直说她是被"夺走"而非谋杀 玛丽是被谋杀的
You keep saying taken instead of murdered. Mary was murdered.
-我当时在场 特鲁  -持枪的男人也在
- I was there, True. - So was the man with the gun.
他在我们到场前就埋伏好了
He was set up before we got there.
所以别管谁没参加葬礼了
So stop worrying about who wasn't at the funeral,
想想谁当时不在那个公园吧
and start asking who wasn't at that park.
你不会是怀疑我们中有叛徒吧
You don't mean one of us.
我知道反正不是我
Well, I know it wasn't me.
桃金娘
Myrtle?
你想聊聊吗
Do you want to talk?
我能看看吗
May I see?
桃金娘
Oh, Myrtle.
这太...
This is so...
你... 听到她说话了
You... heard her?
你希望能听到她的歌声
You wish you could hear her.
你想学习阅读
You want to learn to read?
玛丽对你唱歌了
Mary sang to you.
玛丽对... 我在努力理解
To... I'm trying.
玛丽对你唱歌了
Mary sang to you.
对这个人
To this person.
关于这个人
About this person?
玛丽唱歌的时候 你听到了...
When Mary sang, you heard...
一些话
Words.
语言
Language.
玛丽在告诉我们什么 你听懂了
Mary was telling us something, and you understood it.
她说的是什么好事吗
Was it something nice?
现在你也来跟我们抢活干了
So now you're after our jobs as well?
你从哪个角度切入调查
What angle are you pursuing?
死者的裙摆吗
Hemlines of the deceased?
我完全有权来这里
I have every right to be here.
不 你他妈的没有
No, you fuckin' don't.
很好 这下我也把杜松子酒当早餐了
Lovely. Now I've had gin for breakfast, too.
手指沾点墨并不代表你是记者 博伊尔
Inky fingers don't make you a reporter, Boyle.
蒙迪巡官
Inspector Mundi.
那些纯化论者怎么会拘留了
Why are those Purists being detained?
他们跟布莱顿小姐之死是否有联系
Is there a connection between them and Miss Brighton's death?
还是你的手下没能抓到玛拉黛
Or was it your detail's failure to catch Maladie?
玛丽是她传达的另一个讯息吗
Is Mary another of her messages?
这事已经讲明白了
That story's been told.
我觉得还不够
I don't believe it has.
我认为这其中有比疯子作怪更庞大的布局
I think there is something much larger at work than one maniac.
你有什么有用的线索吗 您是...
Have you got information I can use, Miss...?
博伊尔 "岗哨报"的艾菲・博伊尔
Boyle. Effie Boyle from "The Sentinel,"
目前还没有
and, well, nothing yet.
但我知道媒体喜欢无缘无故
But I do know the Touched are being vilified in the press,
诬陷附魔人
often for no reason.
杀死玛丽・布莱顿的就是附魔人
It was a Touched that killed Mary Brighton.
你要是有其他线索 来找我
You learn more than that, come calling.
所以你恰好路过玛丽・布莱顿的葬礼
So you just happened by Mary Brighton's funeral.
没人告诉过你们葬礼信息
Nobody told you about the service.
我们在外面走着
We were out walking.
你住最南边 在玛斯特磨坊工作
You live in the south end, work at Marster's Mill.
葬礼离你那可有6.4公里
That's four miles out of your way.
我们四处巡回工作
We's peripatetic.
-听着 我说过了...  -跟我说说
- Look, I told you... - Tell me.
-我们在路上散步  -然后你停下来对着悲痛欲绝的一家人
- We were walking. - And you stopped to yell obscenities
说些污言秽语
at a grieving family.
就凭这点你就该进号子
You're already going to jail.
自我表达凭什么要蹲号子
You can't put us in for expressing ourselves.
不 不 我准备以攻击警员的罪名把你关进去
No. No, I'm putting you in for assaulting a police officer.
这计划我喜欢
Well, I like that plan.
猿人来了...
Enter the Ape...
猿人 等等 那个拳击手吗
The Ape? Wait. The boxer?
大名鼎鼎的"东区猿人"吗
The East End Ape?
他是... 是弗兰克・蒙迪吗
Is that... Is that Frank Mundi?
-是蒙迪巡官  -不 没事了
- Inspector Mundi. - Whew. No. You're all right.
是这样 几个西装革履的人
Look, a couple of guys in suits approached us
在纯化论者聚会上找到我们
at a Purist meeting, all right?
我不认识那个要我们去的人 但...
I don't know the guy who said go, but...
他给了我这个
he gave us this.
说他们要把附魔人和体面人葬在一起
Said they were burying a Touched with decent folk,
要我们去闹事
and we should call 'em out.
很好 那就6点在楼下主宿舍见
Great, that's 6:00 in the main dormitory downstairs.
谢谢
Thank you.
又来两个 所以我们可以...
That's another two, so we can...
你好 抱歉 你是新来孤儿院吗
Hi. Sorry, are you new to The Orphanage?
好 你会说任何语言或者方言吗
Okay, do you speak any languages or dialects?
哪些语言
Yeah? What are they?
警察 教堂 纯化论者...
Cops, the church, the Purists...
以及戴面具的怪胎
and our masked freaks.
讨厌我们的大有人在
There's no shortage of people who hate us.
但只有少数人权力够大或有创意到
But only a few are powerful or inventive enough
能悄无声息地把克鲁斯从监狱里弄出来
to have gotten Kroos out of prison undetected.
玛拉黛
Maladie?
克鲁斯以前是她的人
Kroos was her man.
她还有人际关系网
And she's still got a network.
他们轻而易举就找到了霍雷肖
They found Horatio easily enough.
吉尔伯特・马森
Gilbert Massen?
什么 马森勋爵
What, Lord Massen?
伟大的白色猎人
The Great White Hunter.
他可不是什么善茬
Oh, he's a piece of work.
我有朋友在他的工厂里说要罢工
I got chums in his factory talkin' about a strike,
因为他就给那一丁点工资
cause he pays a pittance!
还很危险
And it's dangerous.
处理的都是炸弹之类的东西
It's bombs and the like they're handlin'.
但你一旦受伤那就自求多福吧
But it's a fine fuck-thee-well if you're injured.
他会把你的头挂墙上当奖杯
He'd stick your head on his wall for a trophy
然后才施舍点养孩子的小钱
'fore he'd give you thruppence to feed your kids.
我又扯上政治了 抱歉
Oh... I've gone all political. Sorry.
不 很振奋人心
No, it was quite rousing.
没聊完呢
No.
好了 那么...
Right. So...
-乞丐王  -他做事没这么张扬
- The Beggar King. - A bit public for him.
但他有奥迪恩
But he runs Odium,
既然我们好不容易找到了他的藏身处...
and since we have a hard-won lead on his address...
我去吧 那地方我熟
I'll take it. I know the area.
只要特鲁夫人不想跟人再打一场
If Mrs. True isn't looking for a rematch.
不想 我准备单独去找马森聊聊
No. I'm going to talk to Massen. Alone.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure that's the way to go?
-他可没有那么好...  -我是说 我会去
- He's hardly gonna fall into... - No, I mean, I'm going to.
今天某时候 我预见到了
Sometime today. I've already seen it.
一开始还不确定我在哪 或是... 将会去哪
Wasn't sure where I was at first, but... or will be.
等等 难道是... 马森杀了玛丽
Wait, does... does that mean Massen killed Mary?
你的预感是这么说的吗
Did the ripplings tell you that?
只能说今天行程不由我安排
They tell me I don't get to plan my own day.
预感又不是藏宝图
They're not treasure maps.
我确定我会有收获 但...
I'll learn something, I'm sure, but...
一旦你了解情况
And once you have?
我是说 如果你预感到
I mean, if you get something
"他就是凶手"
in the way of, uh, "he did it."
那我就会回来告诉你们
Then I will bring that information back here.
我可没打算袭击一个上议院的贵族
I'm not planning to attack a Peer of the Realm
更何况他家戒备森严
inside his well-guarded house.
当然 但你的计划
Hmm, sure, but what you mean to happen
和你实际采取的措施通常都...
and what actually happens in the thick of it...
不仅仅是你 特鲁
It's not just you, True.
每个人都要谨慎冷静
Everyone has to keep their heads.
玛丽不能死得不明不白 也不能再搭上一条命
Mary's death needs to be answered, and not with another death.
这也不仅仅关乎对错
And it's not just about what's right.
我们现在是众矢之的
We're hated right now.
我们第一反应不能以怨报怨
Our first response cannot be hate.
否则就会被游街示众
We'll be lined up in the streets.
搞不好他们杀玛丽的用意就在此
And they may have killed Mary exactly for that purpose.
让我们犯些万劫不复的错误
Make us do something they can rain hell on us for.
听到没 安妮也这么想 她可是心狠手辣
See? Annie agrees, and she's terrible.
-我也同意啊  -太好了
- And so do I. - Good.
-保持冷静  -好 奥古斯都・毕德罗呢
- Level heads. - All right. Augustus Bidlow?
嗯 我们该杀了他
Yeah, we should murder him.
我同意派南斯 他们办的那个派对
I'm with Penance. That party they thrown,
瞧见了他怎么对她的
seeing how he treated her,
我差点就要摘手套了
I nearly pulled off me gloves.
还有拉维妮娅・毕德罗
Lavinia Bidlow, as well.
你不会只写了你认识的人吧
Or are you just writing down people you know?
阿玛莉亚告诉她我们要去公园
Amalia told her we were going to the park.
-而且她还知道我们的路线  -不过
- And she knew where I'd be coming from. - Still,
虽然她有点高姿态 但多亏她才有现在的孤儿院
she might be a bit over-puckered, but she's the reason we've got all this.
资助我学医的那家人...
The family that sponsored my medical training...
把我从牙买加带到英国...
That brought me from Jamaica to England...
在他们家待了一周 我差点游回老家
A week in their house, and I almost swam back.
没那么歧视我的人 都让我自生自灭
I've been left for dead by men with less contempt.
虽然毕德罗小姐有一番好意
Now, Miss Bidlow, she means well,
我也知道她为附魔之人给予帮助
and I know she does good work for the Touched,
但不等于说她就是朋友
but it doesn't make her a friend.
所以她和她那个观鸟的弟弟都要记在名单上
So she goes on the list with her terrible, bird-watching brother.
他可是罪魁祸首 你知道吗他...
He's the ringleader. You know he...
喜欢... 鸟
Likes... birds.
鸟都蠢死了
Birds are stupid.
你是时候去告诉他了
And it's high time you told him that.
什么 去跟他说话... 不行
What? Go and talk... No!
-我应该做安妮的任务  -跟踪杀手吗
- I should do Annie's. - Track an assassin?
得了吧 小派 你可以用伞扎他
Come on, Pen, you can give Bidlow the old parasol.
没聊完呢
No!
不好意思
Sorry.
科森斯医生 下面有几个人病得不轻
Doctor Cousens, we got a few peaky ones down there.
你还好吗
How are you holding up?
我儿子奈杰尔还不清楚发生了什么事
my Nigel doesn't really understand what's going on.
但我会尽量保持振作
But I'm keeping my chins up.
有时候自我安慰能有奇效
Sometimes pretending you feel good makes you feel better.
-相信我  -好了
- Trust me. - All right.
我们去看看病人吧
Let's see to those patients.
-别鲁莽行事  -知道了
- Don't do anything rash. - I won't.
我是在说派南斯
I was talking to Penance.
你要不要该带上德西雷去马森家
Shouldn't you take Désirée with you to Massen's?
我应该这么做 可我没带
I should. But I don't.
开局你就剑走偏锋啊 汤米
That's a pungent gambit, Tommy.
弗兰克
Frank.
Frank!
你一直跟纯化论者搞在一起
You've been mixing with the Purists.
煽动他们
Stirring them up.
你是想吓唬附魔之人
Did you want to scare the Touched,
让他们觉得和你一起才安全吗
so you could tell 'em they was only safe with you?
首先 谁...
Uh, first of all, who...
纯化论者是什么玩意儿
Who are the fucking Purists?
这不是我写的
That's not mine.
你觉得我还会留下矛头直指我的证据
You really think I'd be handing out personalized evidence?
斯旺大人
Master Swann.
需要帮忙吗
Any assistance required?
不用 谢谢
Uh, no, thank you.
我们闹着玩呢 会小点声的
Just a bit of sport. We'll keep quiet.
我们会馆只接待会员
This is a members only establishment.
请你滚出去 谢谢
And you need to fuck off. Please.
对 滚吧 谢谢
Uh, yes, uh, do fuck off. There's a lad.
你想想看
Look. Think about this.
如果他们说这是其他某位勋爵
If they'd said it was Lord Such-and-What,
你就会收集证据 派人跟踪他
you'd be gathering evidence. Having him followed.
像个侦探一样
Behaving like a detective.
是有人拿你当枪使了
Someone pointed you and pulled your trigger.
你讨厌我 大家都知道
It's no secret that you loathe me.
这也不能证明你是无辜的
That don't mean you're innocent.
我什么时候说过...
When... When have I ever claimed...
等等 你是在说凶杀案
Wait. Are you talking about the shooting?
我不是凶手
I'm not a murderer.
-我跟玛丽无冤无仇  -她是你的情敌
- I had nothing against Mary. - She was a rival.
我想 你知道她不是
I think you know she wasn't.
我会告诉你我当天的行踪
Look, I... I will provide you with my whereabouts.
我只是想了解阿玛莉亚・特鲁
I wanted to learn about Amalia True,
而我目前所知道的 就是离她远点
and what I've learned is stay away.
-我和这事没关系  -肯定有关
- I am not a part of this. - 'Course you are.
哪怕不是你 就是那些和你下棋的花花公子
And if it ain't you, it's one of them toffs you play chess with.
其实我们管下棋叫起司因为...
Oh, uh, actually we call it cheese because we...
权贵压榨无权无势之人
It's rich men grinding up them who's helpless
夺走他们每一分血汗钱
for extra penny on the pound,
夺走芝麻大点的土地所有权 或者是身体
or, or the rights to a patch of sand. Or a fuck.
-说完了吗  -我俩结束了 斯旺
- Are we done? - Oh, we're done, Swann.
彻底结束
Across the board.
我们之前的小计划 我欠的债 都还清了
And our little arrangement, my debt, is done.
因为现在我有了你的把柄
Cause I got something over you now.
我他妈不在乎了
I don't fucking care.
-翻译  -安尼尔・布林・克劳斯
- Translators. - Aneel Bring Klaus?
对 带上克劳斯 还有说外语的人
Yes, bring Klaus. Anyone who speaks another language,
或者是擅长已消失的语言的人
or who studied a dead language really well.
我们这里只有会法用拉丁语的
I've only got law Latin.
这就麻烦了吗
Oh, it's trouble.
亲亲的时候你随时都行 现在要你帮忙了就不行
Well, you can sneak out for a kiss anytime, but not when I need your help?
-安尼尔 你知道我不会...  -我会来的
- Aneel, you know I wouldn't ask... - No, of course, I'll do it.
谢谢你 爱你 对的 6点
Thank you. I love you. Yeah. Six o'clock.
毕德罗先生
Mr. Bidlow.
阿代尔小姐
Miss Adair.
你怎么...
Uh, what are you...
拉维妮娅知道你来这儿了吗
Uh, so, does Lavinia know you're here?
我知道这里不欢迎我
I know very well that I'm not welcome here.
不是的 我们欢迎你 这...
No, you are. You are. It's, it's...
很高兴见到... 有人看到你吗
It's wonderful to... Did, did anybody see you?
你看起来很紧张
You seem a bit nervous.
我是说 我向来如此
Well, I mean, I usually am,
你好吗 天 不是
but, but you're well? No, Lord, no.
当然不是 抱歉我...
No, of course. I'm so sorry. Um...
我要向布莱顿小姐致以最诚挚的悼念
May I offer my most sincere condolences about Miss Brighton?
她没有给你朋友们带来乐子
She wouldn't have been entertaining to your friends,
所以你也不必惺惺作态
so you needn't grieve overly.
拉维妮娅要我这么做的
Lavinia made me do it.
她 她说我们交往对你不好
She, she, she said it would be bad for you.
-对我不好  -没错 所以我才疏远你
- Bad for me? - Yes, that's why I did it.
她说如果我不这样 就会有坏事...
She said if I didn't, that there would be cons...
等等
Wait.
等等 确实是坏事
Wait, it wa... It was bad.
-所以 这有多糟  -你在跟我开玩笑吗
- So, how is it bad? - Are you making a joke of this?
你不能 不可能…有这么深刻
You can't, you can't p... Possibly have had any deep,
情感上的… 联结…
emotional conn... connection to...
不 我都在说什么啊 我全说错了
Oh, no, I'm saying, I'm saying this all wrong.
我全说错了
I'm saying it wrong.
我以为这是最绅士的做法
I thought it was the gentlemanly thing to do.
谋杀吗
Murder?
-不好意思你说什么  -你是个怪物
- I'm sorry, what? - Oh, you are a monster.
你会进监狱的
And you're gonna go to prison.
-我不在乎你多有钱  -发生什么了
- I don't care how rich you are. - What's happening?
怎么了 现在是什么情况
What's happening? I don't know what's happening.
你刚承认你谋杀了玛丽・布莱顿
You just confessed to the murder of Mary Brighton,
我做了个蜂蜡录音机
and I made a wax recording of it.
-破烂原型机  -阿代尔小姐
- Fuckin' prototype. - Miss Adair.
-你这个人糟糕透顶  -是的 我知道
- You are a terrible person! - Yes, I know. I know!
但…不是我杀的… 需要我帮忙吗…
But I... I didn't kill Miss... Can I...
不用 我很好
Uh, I'm fine.
我是在说派对的事情
I was referring to the party.
都是我的…糟透了… 我当时粗鲁至极
It's my... awful... I was just abominably rude.
那天之后我就难以入睡
And I've barely slept since.
听到这些事以后 我想联系你 分担你的悲痛
When I heard what happened, I wanted to reach out to you in your grief,
但这…这看起来太像乘虚而入…
and it just... it seemed... It seemed opportunistic, or...
你 玛丽不是你杀的吗
You, you didn't kill Mary?
这… 这不是好事吗…
Is... is that bad? Um, it's...
肯定不是你杀的
Of course you didn't.
你那么温文尔雅
You're as gentle as a blush.
但你还是糟糕透顶
But you're still terrible.
是的
Yeah.
告诉我 我要怎么做才能弥补
Tell me just anything that I can do to make amends.
我哭过了
I cried,
虽然听起来很小肚鸡肠 但是…
which seems petty now to think about, but...
我… 我不太知道怎么和男性相处
I don't... I don't have a lot of experience with men.
尤其是你这种权贵 就我所见…
Certainly not of your class, which from what I've seen...
是的 没有人比有钱人更加残暴
No, nobody is quite as barbaric as the well-to-do.
你的露西让我明白了这些
Your Lucy had me figured out.
阿代尔小姐 我愿意付出一切
Miss Adair, I would give anything
只要你能把那天永远忘掉
if you would erase that day from your mind.
这不是那么简单的
That's not how it works.
确实
No.
不是
也不该这样
Nor should it be.
那就好好记住我的错误
Remember my transgressions,
也许哪一天 我能重新赢得你的信任
so that I may re-earn your trust honestly, over time.
如果…
If we are...
如果我们要互相了解
If we are to be acquainted,
我会努力…
I shall endeavor...
不对不对 去他妈的了解
No, no, no, no! Damn acquaintance.
了解太累人了 我只是…
Acquaintance is exhausting. I just...
我想做你的朋友 阿代尔小姐
I want to be your friend, Miss Adair.
我想… 做你的朋友
I want... I want to become your friend.
那些花是你送给玛丽的
You sent the flowers for Mary.
-花环是不是太过了 太花哨了  -没有
- Was the wreath too much? It was, it was garish. - No.
你觉得人是你姐姐杀的吗
Do you think your sister did the murder then?
你说什么
What?
我只想问问
I was only askin'.
或许是你的语气不对
Maybe it's your tone of voice.
-你怎么来这的  -我很灵活
- How'd you get there? - I'm Nimble.
不 我是说我叫"灵活"
No, I'm Nimble,
就好像人家问 "你最近怎么样 灵活杰克
as in, "How do you do? Nimble Jack.
-但朋友们都叫我…"  -回答我的问题
- But my friends all call me..." - You didn't answer my question.
我也想知道你这样的甜心怎么会在这
Well, I'm wondering what a sweet thing like you is doing 'round here.
我就在这长大的
I'm from around here.
-看来他们不记得你了  -不 他们记得
- They don't seem to remember you. - No, they did.
-你想要什么  -喝一杯吧
- What do you want? - A drink, maybe.
简单吃点吗 三个牧师家做的鳗鱼派很好吃
Light supper? Three Vicars does a nice eel pie.
还有私人包间
Private room.
是我太心急了吗
Too fast?
-你为乞丐王工作  -只能算合作
- You work for the Beggar King. - With.
得看情况
On occasion.
那伙人里一个拉小提琴的
One of his gang plays the fiddle.
把地址透露给了那个好斗寡妇
Gave up an address to a belligerent widow.
拉小提琴的说他尝试反抗 但是…
Fiddler said he tried to fight, but...
她把他摁住了 逼他说出来
she got him pinned, and squeezed it out of him.
可怜的德克兰 连个靠得住的人都没
Poor Declan. He really can't find decent help.
所以他希望你不要杀了奥迪恩
Which is why he'd prefer you don't kill Odium.
拜托 那不是乞丐王下的命令
This wasn't the King's work. Come on.
玛拉黛的手下射杀了那个布莱顿女孩
Maladie's man shoots the Brighton girl.
乞丐王的得力手下追杀那个寡妇
Beggar King's chief enforcer goes after the widow.
什么人在操纵这场好戏
Someone's puttin' on a show.
我需要确切知道是"什么人"
I need more than "someone."
奥迪恩屁都不知道
Odium knows fuck all.
他是个蠢货 老天保佑 他只是个打手
He's dim, bless him, and he's in for another thrashing.
但他在就能相安无事
But he's necessary to keep the peace.
充充门面
Keep appearances.
别管奥迪恩了
Leave Odium be,
你烧掉的那些鸦片就既往不咎
and the opium you torched is bygones.
做朋友
Friends.
或者说… 同仇敌忾
Or... common enemy.
她在哪
Where is she?
这些人 他压根不在乎
This lot, he doesn't care about.
-看起来他们都还记得你  -低调点
- Seems like they all remember you. - Just keep your head down.
从来不 以后也不
Never have, never will.
感谢你接见我
Thank you for seeing me.
毕德罗家族是我的老朋友
The Bidlows are old friends.
我和拉维妮娅或许时常意见相左
Lavinia and I may not see eye-to-eye on everything,
但她不会在无关紧要的人身上浪费时间
but she doesn't waste her time with trifling people.
我觉得她很器重你
I think she regards you quite highly.
我欠她良多 孤儿院里所有人都是
I owe her a great deal. Everyone at The Orphanage does.
请见谅 我听闻了布莱顿小姐的噩耗
Forgive me. I did read about your girl, Miss Brighton.
我想你已经听过了足够多的吊唁
I suspect you've had all the condolences you have room for,
不如让我请你喝杯雪莉酒吧
so may I offer you a sherry?
现在喝酒有点早 但…
Bit early, but...
我能再大胆猜测一下吗
And may I also offer a conjecture?
你觉得我和你朋友的死有关
You think that I had something to do with your friend's death.
是吗 那真是帮我省时间
Did you? It would save me such a lot of time.
恐怕我要让你失望了
I'm going to have to disappoint you, I'm afraid.
俱乐部里也无人愿意领这个赏
No one at the club is vying for credit either,
但我会多留心的
though I will keep an ear out.
感谢
Appreciated.
但是 我需要的是你的看法
But, what I could really use is your perspective,
作为一名军人 以及既有秩序中的权威人士
as a military man and a powerful member of the established order.
无论是谁谋害玛丽・布莱顿 都是在发表公开声明
Whoever did have Mary Brighton killed was making a public statement.
就像踏上舞台并且杀死六个人
Like stepping on stage and murdering six people.
-那是不同的  -一模一样
- A different message. - The same messenger.
那位持枪杀人犯 克鲁斯
That gunman, Kroos.
-他已经死了  -真可惜
- Well, he's taken care of. - Shame.
本来可以指望他开口的
He might have talked.
不如假设 你杀了她
You killed her. Let's say.
恕我冒犯 这种假设还挺有帮助的
If you'll indulge me, I've found this a useful exercise.
假设不是玛拉黛 或某位前任
Let's assume it wasn't Maladie or an erstwhile lover,
而是某个掌管大局的人
but someone with a broader view.
你就做导致玛丽死亡的那个主谋
You'll take the part of the mastermind behind Mary's death.
你来当那个愤怒的巡官吗
And you'll be the irate inspector?
我是玛丽
I'll be Mary.
你为什么要杀了我
Why would you want me dead?
我并不想杀了你
I doubt that I do.
我都不知道你的"转变"是什么
I'm not entirely clear what your "turn" is.
算是某种灯标吗
A beacon of some sort?
你很善良 也没什么恶意
Anyway benign, and you're an inoffensive woman.
也没当过激进分子 我猜想
No history of radicalism, I assume.
那为什么死的是我
So why me?
为什么不杀了那个寡妇 特鲁夫人
Why not kill that widow, Mrs. True?
她是个任意妄为的女人
She's a willful creature,
是这群杂七杂八女巫的首领
and the leader of this motley coven.
那她一定树敌无数
Which means she must have enemies.
她的死亡或许可悲 但不会出人意料
Her death might be tragic, but perhaps not unexpected.
与此相反 你是位纯洁
You, on the other hand, are a pure
无可指摘的女性
and blameless woman.
身着洁白长裙
And all in white, no less.
雕塑般的美貌 一袭红褐色的头发
A statuesque beauty with a mass of auburn hair
又大又亮的眼睛…
and great shining eyes...
天啊 我不止是灯标
Christ, I'm not just a beacon.
我更像是座灯塔
I genuinely resemble a lighthouse.
这不只是警告
It isn't just a warning.
这和希望有关
It's about hope.
是把希望从孤儿院众人的心中抽走
It's about pulling the heart out of the orphans.
我也这么想
I would think so.
事实上我要说 布莱顿小姐
In fact, I would say, Miss Brighton,
你是战争的受害者
that you are a casualty of war.
所以我们已经开战了
So we're at war.
几年前 一场瘟疫席卷了这座城市
A few years back, a pestilence ran through this city.
一些无政府主义的阴谋家
Some anarchic cabal
找到或发明出了一种嘲弄上帝的力量
found or developed a power that mocks God.
扰乱破坏了k的自然法则
That molests and disfigures His natural law.
这是对大英帝国的稳定与和谐
It was an attack on the stability, the harmony,
进行的侵犯
if you will, of the empire.
我们必须告诉这场处心积虑的瘟疫的受害者
And we must show the victims of this deliberate plague
他们并不特别 他们不是一个团体
that they are not special. They are not a community.
受害者是他们唯一的标签
Victims is all they have license to be.
如果我是你要找的杀手 看着吧
If I am your killer revealed, behold the lion,
雄狮般的大英帝国
Great Britain.
无与伦比的帝国
An empire unparalleled
会不惜一切代价保护自己
and unmerciful in its self-preservation.
我的敌人是整个英格兰
My enemy is England.
-范围小多了 感谢上帝没白来一趟  -我说的是你要找的主谋
-Well, that narrows it down. Thank God I came. -I said your killer.
你的敌人 布莱顿小姐
Your enemy, Miss Brighton,
是造成了这场瘟疫的人渣
is the scum who caused this plague,
是把它作为力量的蠢货
the fools who call it power,
是那个本该知道
and the woman who should have known
你会在公园里发生什么的女人
what would happen to you in that park.
除非 她早已心知肚明
Unless, of course, she did.
所以 他毫无悔意地承认了
So, he confessed without confessing.
那真是厉害
It was honestly impressive.
我应该带着你的录音机去
I should have worn your recording frame.
但他没有交代消息来源
But he didn't give up his source.
他没有直截了当地承认
He never flat-out said.
即使我们有证据 马森也知道我们没法动他
Even if we had proof, Massen knows we couldn't touch him.
-我可以  -不会又要进行这种对话吧
- I could touch him. - Oh, please tell me we're not havin' this talk again.
不 即使是他下的命令
No. Even if he gave the order,
他背后有更大的组织
he's part of something much bigger.
把他揪出来 立马就有人顶上
Pull out one piece, it would be replaced in a day.
况且 不能用暴力解决问题
And damn it, it's wrong.
他是个活生生的人 该死
He's a human being who's alive, damn it.
可我们还得想办法应对
We still need a response.
如果我们放任杀戮 只会越来越糟
If we let murder slide, it will only slide down.
不管怎样接下来都会更糟
Whatever's next will be worse.
连我都知道这是对的
Even I know that's true.
听说他有个仓库
Well, some of the lads say he has a warehouse
装满了可以点燃的弹药
full of munitions we could torch.
晚上好像没人看守
I don't think there's anyone in there at night.
太便宜他了 但这只是个开始
He deserves much worse, but it would be a start.
都同意吗
All in favor?
你这个蠢货
You fuckin' idiot.
你还不如去上议院游行
You might as well have marched in the House of Lords
顺便撒泡尿
and had a slash!
督察长被狠狠骂了一顿
Superintendent's had an earful.
我在追查一条线索
I was pursuing a lead.
除非玛拉黛在那个俱乐部喝茶
Unless Maladie was havin' tea in that club,
督察长还能信你的鬼话
Superintendent don't want to hear it.
蒙迪 给我进来
Mundi! Get in here!
没事的
It'll be fine.
-我可以要你的桌子吗  -你想得美
- Can I have your desk? - You can cop a mouse.
-放开他  -他造谣我的事
- Let him go. - But he lies about me.
他会闭嘴的
He'll stop.
他会辞职 而且永远不会再打扰你...
And, and he'll resign, and, and he'll never bother you again...
你在撒谎 我还听说你很实在呢
Oh, now you're lying! I heard you wouldn't.
那些报纸
And, whoa, the papers!
他们说我杀了玛丽 他们说我疯了
They say I killed Mary. They call me crazy.
我从没做过
I never did it.
我只杀天使 大多数时候
I only kill angels. Mostly.
我非常喜欢玛丽
I liked Mary so much.
她本来是我的宠物 睡在我的肚皮上
She was gonna be my pet, and sleep on my belly.
-你可是要绞死她  -我们有很多计划
- You were gonna hang her. - Well, we had a lot of plans.
她说那个警探既聪明又诚实
She talked about the detective who was smart, and honest.
他很悲伤 所以她没嫁给他
And she didn't marry him because he was sad.
看在玛丽的份上 你会...
For Mary's sake, will you...
-你会放过他吗  -她没有用了 亲爱的
- Will you let him live? - Oh, she doesn't have a sake, love.
她死了 冰冷地躺在那个箱子里
She's dead. She's all cold in that box.
每个人都哭着把它掩埋
Everyone crying as they lowered it in the hole,
还唱着什么工作日的歌
singin' about the workday, and what.
你... 你当场了
Y... You were there?
当然
Of course.
我在箱子里
I was in the box.
我还抱了抱她
I had a little cuddle.
但她闻起来不一样了
But she smelled different.
我不认为那是她最喜欢的裙子
And I will not believe that was her favorite dress.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想所有人别再说谎
I want everyone to stop lying.
你能搞定吗
Can you see to that?
我尽量
I will try.
我得考虑我的名誉
I have to think about my reputation.
万物一去不复返
Things never come back when they go away.
在这里 快
-Ha! In here! Now!
天啊
Oh, Christ.
不
Oh, no!
这也算是在撒谎
That's a form of lying!
不
No!
蒙迪
Mundi.
见鬼 是她 玛拉黛
Fuck, it's her! It's Maladie!
他抓住她了
He fucking got her!
没错 现在没那么可怕了... 好了
Right. Not so scary now... All right.
公正
Justice.
得给她公正的审判
She gets justice from us.
谁敢动她 我就揍扁他
I'll have badge and balls off any man who tries that.
得给她公正的审判
She gets justice from us.
好的 大家
Okay, everybody.
准备好了
Ready?
好了
Okay.
很好 桃金娘
Right. Myrtle?
大声清楚地说
Nice and loud.
桃金娘
Myrtle.
慢一点
A little slower.
再说一遍
Again?
我知道了
I know it!
黑暗
The darkness.
黑暗 黑暗之前
Dark. Um, uh, before the dark?
在黑暗来临前过来
Uh, come before the dark.
没错没错
Sí, sí.
那是最后几句吧
Was that near the end?
再说一遍
Again.
我朋友说仓库...
My mate said the warehouse... Yeah.
就是那间
It's that one.
入口在另一头
And the entrance is on the far side.
那帮守卫呢
And that lot?
我答应了派南斯
I promised Penance.
-轮到你了  -不 没轮到我去拿杯子
- Because it's your turn again! - No, it ain't my turn to get the cup.
-去拿杯子的总是我  -叫你去就去
- I always got to get the cup. - Just do what you're told, all right?
如果工头发现我们走了...
-If the foreman finds out we've left...
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
靠 这是什么鬼东西
Bloody hell. What the blazes is that?
你觉不觉得派南斯其实很可怕
Do you ever think maybe Penance is frightening?
你打算怎么做 给他们递朵雏菊
And what were you gonna do? Hand 'em a daisy?
-呆在外面  -我可会放火
- Stay outside. - I'm the one with the fire.
我们得确保里面没人死在火里
And we need to make sure no one goes up in it.
这是你自找的
Your funeral.
-没人  -看起来没问题
- No one. - Looks good.
船将于黎明启航
Due to ship out at dawn.
真想看看他的表情
I'd like to see his face.
开几个箱子 保证货是对的
Let's open a couple. Make sure we have the right shipment.
你确定警卫睡着了
You sure the guards are still sleepin'?
我们还有时间
We have time.
不好 我就是... 有种感觉
Yeah. No, I just have that... that feeling.
露西
Lucy.
打开箱子
Open the crate.
现在我们知道为什么战况不佳了
Well, now we know why the war isn't going better.
他们发誓里边是军火 特鲁
They swore they were weapons, True.
他们一定在为...
They must be workin' for...
-你怎么注意到的  -是预感
- How'd you cop it? - It was the rippling.
你提到了马森打猎 他的战利品
Your talk of Massen's hunting. His trophies.
你得去他的书房才有印象
You'd have to have been in his study to call that up.
要不是看过两次 我可能就忽略了
I might have missed it if I hadn't seen it twice.
-都怪我这大嘴巴  -还有这个非常方便的计划
- My clapper of a mouth. - And then this perfectly convenient plan.
没有人看守的弹药仓库
Warehouse of munitions no one's really guarding?
老天啊 事实就已经摆在这了
Christ, it was all already there.
总是问问题 还无故缺席
The questions, the absences,
你故意发誓没偷钱 所以我们会认为你偷了
the money you swore you didn't steal so we'd assume you did.
-就知道这招太老套了  -你打扫我的书房
- I figured that'd get a bit tired. - You clean my study,
却懒得铺自己的床 我真是个傻子
but you can't make your own bed. I am such an idiot.
我不知道他们要对玛丽做什么
I didn't know what they was plannin' for Mary.
-我发誓  -他们还能做什么
- I swear. - What else would they have ever done,
在你告诉他们玛丽是指引者之后
after you told them Mary was a beacon?
-你想怎么样 特鲁  -我希望是其他人
- What do you want, True? - I want it to be someone else!
我希望是哈莉特或者琼
I want it to be Harriet, or Jo.
或者是那个人 她... 海伦
Or the one who does, she... Helen.
-她叫莫德  -那个做侧手翻的人 操
- Maud. - The one who does the cartwheels. Fuck!
你是第一个女人 第一个
You were the first woman, the first woman
走进那扇门的女人
to walk through those doors!
是我可以依靠而不是需要我保护
The one I could lean on instead of protecting,
和我同样理解
that understood the world
-这个世界的人  -你懂个屁的世界
- the way that I do. - You don't know fuck about the world.
你所有的战场故事
All your war stories.
多到你都记不清具体 真糟糕
You don't know which war. Oh, oh, it's awful.
因为在战场上留下了尸体
'Cause you've left bodies on the field,
你们就身心受挫了
and you're all damaged.
我把我的儿子弄成了碎片
I broke my son to pieces.
我抱起了刚出生的孩子 却杀了他
I held my baby, and it killed him.
这一切远没有我说得那么快
And it wasn't sudden like I said.
身体断裂 是突然发生的
The breaks, they were sudden.
但是他... 他还没死
But he... he held on.
接着他开始尖叫
And he screamed.
他比出生时哭得还要久......
He screamed longer than I did pushin' him out...
在他彻底死去之前
'fore his heart gave.
你来告诉我 我们能不能感同身受
So you tell me, are we sisters?
我已经三年没有碰过其他人了
It's been three years since I've touched another person.
马森说他会找到治疗方法
And Massen, he says he'll find a cure.
他当然会这么说
Of course he tells you that.
可你是怎么跟我们说的
And what are you telling us?
一个更好的世界
A better world?
但凡他们有一丁点儿的机会
How many of your precious orphans would be lining up
你那些宝贝孤儿们中会有多少个会排起长队
to be free of your better world
从你那个更好的世界解脱
if they had half a chance?
这不该是这样的
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what happened.
你怎么会知道本该发生什么
How do you know how it's supposed to be?
是你干的吗
Did you do this?
是你制造了这一场噩梦吗
Did you make this nightmare?
我只是被抛下了
I just got left behind.
当然了 你有什么本事
'Course you got left behind. What good are you?
你 还配当领头的
You, a leader?
当女孩需要你时 你却在外面嫖娼...
You're out whoring when your girls need...
你的老板告诉我 我们正面临战争
Your boss told me today that we're at war.
不是我挑起的
I didn't start it.
我甚至没自愿上场 但他说对了
I didn't even volunteer. But he's right.
但愿他告诉过你战争时如何处置间谍
I hope he told you what happens to spies during wartime.
是这样吗
Is that what this is?
这是有交战规则的
There's rules of engagement.
而不仅仅是你把失败发泄在别人身上
And not just you needing to take your failure out on someone.
你认为派南斯还会原谅你吗
You think Penance will forgive you for this?
难道玛丽就会吗
You think Mary would?
这话我就听不懂了
And that's where you lose me.
你在伦敦的日子永远结束了
You're finished in London. Forever.
我和安妮会送你上船 你就留在船上
Annie and I will put you on a boat and you'll stay on it
养好伤了就他妈给我滚蛋
until you're well and fucking gone.
把你知道的都告诉我
And you'll tell me everything you know.
所有事 懂了吗
Everything. Yes?
真的军火库在哪
Where are the real munitions?
起火了 靠
A fire? Oh, no!
-到处都起火了  -怎么回事
- It's everywhere. - How?
我的人只是在巡视
My men were just doing the rounds.
全都爆炸了 一片混乱
Everything exploded, and it was, it was chaos!
工厂有人受伤吗
Was anyone at the factory harmed?
没有 就是工厂...
No, it was the factory, the...
幸运的是 没有人受伤
Foreman Luckily no one was hurt.
保罗街的仓库建筑
The Paul Street storage building.
了解了
I see.
这不在计划之中
This wasn't the plan.
这不是你的计划吗
Well, it was your plan, wasn't it?
我只是你的工具
I'm just your instrument.
我一直都是你的工具
I've always been your instrument.
你为什么不用我
Why won't you play me?
为什么
Why?
我还是想不通
I still can't make sense of it.
-怎么会是露西  -我们早该看穿了
- Lucy. - We should have seen it a long time ago.
我只希望她是唯一一个
I just hope she's the only one.
在我们埋葬玛丽的同一天失去了...
Losing her the same day we buried M...
无论如何 我很感激你饶了她一命
Anyway, I'm grateful you spared her life.
我没有
I didn't.
你有
You did.
那个白痴胸针
That idiotic pin.
她本可以逃走 但她不肯丢下它
She could have gotten away, but she wouldn't leave without it.
这也是我的计划
That was always my plan, of course.
她说我不知道这里的人正在经历什么
She said I had no idea what anyone is going through here.
我恨她竟然说的是对的
I hate that she's right.
但我没法... 和他们交心
But I can't... get close to them.
露西就是活生生的例子
Lucy's proof of that.
她要是再敢在伦敦露脸
She shows her face in London again though,
拿件首饰可救不了她的命
it'll take more than a piece of jewelry to save her.
那要是换个大点的首饰呢
So, um, a bigger piece of jewelry?
一条腰带 或者是一顶帽子
A belt, maybe, or a hat?
特鲁 我不能给她做一整套衣服
True, I can't make her a whole outfit.
我是我见过的最奇怪的人
You are the strangest person I've ever met.
这也是我信任你的原因
It's why you're the one I trust.
奥吉古斯都・毕德罗的能力
Augie Bidlow's Touched.
是鸟 他能控制它们
Birds. He sort of controls them.
不是吧
I'll be damned.
你认为这就是拉维妮娅接手的原因吗
Do you think that's why Lavinia took up the cause?
他很确信她不知道
He's certain she doesn't know.
我觉得他很怕告诉她
I think he's afraid to tell her.
但是他不怕告诉你
But he's not afraid to tell you.
你在这儿啊
You're here!
-他们在这儿  -我们在这里
- They're here! - We are here.
-你不会相信的  -怎么了 桃金娘
- You won't believe it. - Myrtle, what's wrong?
没有 没出什么事
No, it's not wrong at all.
哈莉特 告诉她们 哈莉特解决了大部分的问题
Harriet, tell them. It was mostly Harriet that worked it out.
不过 我帮忙翻译了法语
I helped with the French, though.
请说吧 哈莉特
Harriet, please.
抱歉... 我不想说错
I'm sorry, it... I don't want to say it wrong.
其实不是我 是桃金娘
And it, it wasn't me. It was Myrtle.
桃金娘能听懂玛丽的歌
Myrtle understood Mary's song. Mostly.
玛丽都不知道歌词的意思...
Even Mary didn't know what her songs meant...
她总是这么说
She always said.
有一些是在抒发感情 相比...
Some of it was more about emotion than...
或者说是情感加语义学
Or emotion plus semantics,
但是她记得很多 她只是不知道如何表达
but she remembered a lot. She just didn't know how to tell us.
桃金娘
Myrtle.
-她说了什么  -她说"你不是一个人"
- What did she say? - Uh, she said, "You're not alone."
-好吧 我认为我们都能感觉到...  -你 特鲁女士
- Well, I think we could all feel that... - You, Mrs. True.
她是对你说的
She said it to you.
她说"阿玛莉亚 我孤独的战士"
She said, "Amalia, my lonely soldier."
还有一些关于军衔的事
Um, something about wearing stripes.
但是这部分...
But that part...
但是她说"我没有离开你"
But she said, "I didn't leave you.
"我去到了 城市的更深处
"I went into, in-inside the city.
我受损了"... "不完整
I was damaged..." uh, "incomplete?
"我需要治疗
"I had to heal.
-但我们快准备好了..."  -这部分是我翻的
- Soon we will all be ready..." - Oh, that part was me.
"但很黑暗 黑暗将我笼罩"
"But it's dark. There's a darkness."
她是对我们所有人说 要我们聚在一起
She said to-to everyone, all of us, to gather,
互相保护
-and protect each other.
因为黑暗
Because of the dark.
还有吗
And was there more?
"来找我
Uh, "Find me.
"让那些愿意的人 伸出援手
"Let them help, those who will,
但请到下面来找我"
but come below and find me."
"在黑暗来临前过来 我们可以拯救..."
Um... "Come before the dark, and we can save..."
到这儿就结束了 这就是当时...
It ended there. That's when...
这些不是玛丽的歌词吧
Those aren't Mary's words, are they?
是有人通过玛丽说的
That was someone else talking through her.
没错
That's right.
那会是谁呢
Then who?
我们需要找的是谁
Who do we need to find?